那只是首在非正式活动中唱的好玩的歌而已
It was a lighthearted song at an informal event.
是的 她会向欧洲道歉
Yeah, she's going to apologize to Europe
因为它几乎和黑死病
'cause it's right up there with the bubonic plague
还有德累斯顿地毯式轰炸一样臭名昭著了
and the carpet bombing at Dresden.
Tommy 你好 Amy 是的
Tommy, hi. Amy. Yeah.
别理Dan 他内分泌失调
Ignore Dan. He's hormonal.
这首歌有趣是因为
The song is funny because
它恰好和她对欧洲的观点相反
it's the opposite of her views on Europe.
等我回来一起去喝一杯?没问题
Drinks when I get back? Okay.
你得像Mike那样做
You need to do it like Mike.
哦 我可不想变成Mike 好吗
Yeah, I don't want to be like Mike, okay?
就是Mike也不想是Mike
Even Mike doesn't want to be like Mike.
你需要打电话给他
You should call him.
我们得让副总统远离一般人
And we need to keep the veep away from regular people
以及他们奇怪的问题
and their awkward questions.
所以要让她身在赫尔辛基而不真在赫尔辛基
So while she's in Helsinki, just keep her out of Helsinki.
哦 棒极了 她给了我一个口袋更少的Leviathan包
- Yeah, wonderful. - She gave me a Leviathan with fewer pockets.
那么最新消息是什么?巴尔干半岛上有人焚烧我的肖像?
So what's the latest? Any burning effigies of me in the Balkans?
瞧你穿着睡衣的样子 我需要唑吡旦 (治疗短期失眠)
Look at You in your jammies. - I need Ambien.
哦 好的
Oh, right.
什么? 这是氟哌酸 (抗菌) 我又没有尿路感染
What? This is Cipro. I don't have a urinary infection.
哦 天哪
Oh, my gosh.
听这个
Listen to this.
这儿的气候很寒冷
The climate here is very cold,
但欢迎很热烈
but the reception here is very warm.
马上就到了 没错
- It's almost there. - Yeah.
不是很棒么?
Isn't it great?
是的 没错 哦 好吧...
Yes, this is. Yeah, well...
Gary 什么?
Gary. - Yeah?
你有我的...?
Did you get my...?
别摆出那副表情
Please don't make that face.
你知道我只在出国的时候才干这个 给我吧
You know I only do this when I go abroad. Come on.
只是上次你戒烟的时候 你情绪起伏很大
It's just last time you stopped, you were so up and down.
听着 我确实非常需要我的小卫士们
Listen, I really do need my little soldiers.
我只是说... 我要我燃烧的红烟头们
- I'm just saying... - I need my flaming redheads.
我不明白... 谢谢
- I don't understand... - Thank you.
那么怎么样了?那首歌在芬兰的反响如何?
So what's going on? How's the song going over in Finland?
有报纸称您是来自特区的恐欧女头领
Some paper is calling you the Europhobic Khaleesi from DC.
恐欧? 不是吧?
Europhobic? Seriously?
那是什么意思? 我害怕说话打字幕么?
What is that supposed to mean? I'm scared of subtitles?
Mike 你拿到
Mike, you got the summary
2008年中立州模拟结果总结了?
of the 2008 swing state modeling?
唔 还没 不过我有一份那份总结的摘要 棒极了
Uh, not yet, but I do have a summary of the summary that's great.
那么...
So...
嘿 Dan
Hey, Dan.
怎么样 Mike? 他妈的这儿真疯狂
- How's it hanging, Mike? - It's fucking insane here.
就像在数学监狱一样 他们用数字强暴你
It's like a math prison. They rape you with numbers.
Mike 你的选民注册大概什么时候能出来?
Mike, what's your voter registration ETA?
马上...吧
Imminent...al.
好吧 Mike 听着 只要告诉我一件事
All right, Mike, listen, just tell me one thing.
你是怎么做到你那套
How do you do that Fozzie Bear,
扮蠢卖萌 胡说八道的招数让媒体喜欢你?
happy guy, wocka-wocka bullshit to get the press to like you?
哦 你想学Mclin演说法 嗯?
Oh, you want to learn to McLin-talk, huh?
记住 那就是演戏
Remember it's a performance.
你得假装你很有魅力
You have to pretend that you're charming.
笑话不好笑也无所谓 别在意
It doesn't matter if the jokes are weak, keep it loose.
故意说些糟糕的笑话 这很天才
Deliberately bad jokes. It's kind of genius.
说明了很多东西
Explains a lot.
呼叫白痴
Call dickhead.
西翼 Jonah 嘿 Jonah 是Mike
- West Wing, Jonah. - Hey, Jonah. It's Mike.
我需要你来这解释统计梦...
I need you to come over here and explain this Dream Metric to...
哦 没错 我刚刚就在找那个
oh, bingo. I was looking for that.
好吧 所以你想要J大牛过去
Okay, so you want J-Rock to come down there
朝你耳朵里吐点来劲的智慧? 是这个意思吧 Mike?
and spit some wicked wisdom in your ear. Is that what I'm hearing, Mike?
瞧 如果你帮我这个忙 我就把你弄回来当副总统队伍里的常驻怪胎
Look, if you do this, I will get you back in as the veep's resident creep.
如果我去那 Mike 人们会想知道我为什么不在欧洲
If I come down there, Mike, people are gonna wonder why I'm not in Europe.
别担心 伙计 我可以帮你掩盖 记住 我以撒谎为生
Don't worry, buddy. I can cover for you. Remember, I lie for a living.
没错 但你做得不怎么样 没人相信你
Yeah, but you don't do it well and nobody believes you.
我知道赫尔辛基这的气温在冰点以下
I realize it's below freezing here in Helsinki,
但我实实在在地
but I certainly am touched
感动于我们今晚收获的热烈欢迎
by the very warm welcome we've received this evening.
非常感谢 谢谢
Thank you very much. Thank you.
你对那首歌有任何想说的吗?
Do you have any comment on the song?
副总统女士
Madam Vice President, would you have made
你会对中东开类似的玩笑吗?
jokes like that about the Middle East?
伙计们 我们很感谢你们的出席
Guys, we really appreciate you coming out,
但请明天再照相 她会道歉吗?
- but let's save the autographs for tomorrow. - Is she going to apologize?
副总统来这... 是为了道歉?
the Vice president is here... - to apologize?
你远离家乡 兄弟
You're a long way from home, mate.
这实际上是等候提问的队伍...
This is really the line of questioning...
兄弟? 哦 你也远离家乡呢 兄弟
Mate? Yeah, you're a long way from home, mate, too.
副总统来这是为了签署贸易协议
The vice president is here to sign a trade agreement
并促成两个伟大国家的一项重要的友谊合作
and forge a very important friendship between two great nations.
明天将会向媒体说明
Press avail tomorrow.
届时我会为你们展示一个小的街头魔术 如何?
At which point I'll perform a little street magic for you, okay?
所以你们都在想着一张牌
So you guys all think of a card.
我在想红心9
I'm thinking nine of hearts.
我在想王(小丑)
I'm thinking joker.
Ooh!
冷淡而充满着敌意
That was cold and hostile.
确定我们没有飞过头而降落在了50年代的俄罗斯?
Sure we didn't overshoot and land in Russia in the 1950s?
哦 那个英国记者怎么了? 我知道
- Yeah, what was with that British reporter? - I know.
你不会希望其中的任何一个紧跟着你
You do not want one of those on your back.
他们会为了一杯热啤酒而出卖祖母的裸照
They will sell nude pics of their grandmothers for a glass of hot beer.
顺说 在机场那里
By the way, that is not the way
那不是Mike的处理方式 好吗?
Mike would have handled that back then at the airport, okay?
如果Mike在 整个航程
If Mike were here, we would have spent the entire flight
我们都会看他玩刮刮卡抽奖卡
watching him do scratcher lotto tickets going,
哦 就差一点 他就没赢过
Oh, so close, every time he lost.
我们能不能就... 哦 我想念Mike
- Could we just... - Yeah, I miss Mike.
哦 瞧 那真友好
Oh, look. That's nice.
上面有张微笑的脸
It's got a smiley face on it.
Selina 你在想怎么用50种方法离开赫尔辛基吗?
Selina, you looking for 50 ways to leave Helsinki?
好吧 伙计们 非常感谢
Okay, guys, thank you very much.
今晚我们不会回答任何问题
We're not taking any questions tonight.
我们得给iPad充电
We've got some iPads to recharge.
但我们会在明早和你们见面 好的 谢谢
But we'll see you in the morning. Okay, thank you.
晚安 回你的吉普去吧 副总统
- Good night. - Just get in the Jeep, veep.
嘿 放轻松 老前辈 骑士在此
Hey, relax, old-timer. Cavalry's here.
我们得向外行人总结这一切
We have to summarize all this for the layman.
耶稣啊 Mike 这太基础了
Jesus, Mike. This is so basic.
这就像回到中学了一样
This is like high school all over again.
我去 老爷爷 你大概仍然从杂志找黄色图片吧
Holy shit, grandpa, you probably still get your porn from magazines.
Mike 把数据要点总结成
Mike, sub the data principles
500 100 还有20个词的版本
to 500, 100, and 20-word versions.
Jonah 是的 先生?
- Jonah. - Yes, sir?
哦 这可是意料之外的组合
Well, this is an unexpected permutation.
Mike? 嗯?
Mike? - Hmm?
唔 副总统认为Jonah的才华可能...
Um, the vice president thought Jonah's talents might be...
我们应该把秘密行动通知国会的
We're supposed to inform Congress of covert operations.
听着 这已经不是像我的食谱那样的选择题了
Now, this isn't a choice like my diet,
而是像我的饮品一样毫无悬念
this is a necessity like my drinking.
我会在24小时内做民意调查
I am going to be taking soundings over the next 24 hours.
国家安全顾问正到处跑
The national security advisor is running around
就像有鹰群从他的JJ里飞出来一样
like he's got eagles flying out of his dick.
你这些大惊小怪的反应 很好地解释了你为什么离了三次婚
All this melodrama really explains your three divorces.
哦 我更想让你的头和你他妈的脖子离一把
Well, I'd like to divorce your head from your fucking neck.
动手吧  好了 听着 Mike 我要你...
Do it. All right, listen, Mike, I need you...
一个人到底可以午餐休息多少次啊?
How many lunch breaks can one guy take?
我刚刚收到了封来自Sue的邮件
So I just got an e-mail from Sue.
某件事把白宫闹得鸡飞狗跳
Something's really got 'em jumping at the White House.
好吧 哦 你得去为那首歌道歉了
Okay, well, you need to go and apologize for the song.
还有 别说笑话 成吗 Dan?
And don't make any jokes, okay, Dan?
因为你那张脸 当你试图表现得迷人
Because with your face, when you attempt to be charming,
结果看起来会很...邪恶
it really does come off as evil.
哦 你还好吧
Yeah. - You doing okay?
你拿到了...? 哦 有梨子
- Did you get the...? - Ooh, they got pears.
我不想吃水果 你有那个吗?
I don't want fruit. Did you get 'em?
是的 我有那个 我有那个
Yes, I got 'em. I got 'em.
哦 别玩了 这是个小包
- Oh, come on. - It's a small bag.
你在抱怨这个礼物? 不 我没有
- Are you complaining about this gift? - No, I'm not.
这包不小 你手太大了
It's not a small bag. Your hands are large.
我爸总说我有双女人的手 好吧...
- My dad always said I had lady's hands. - Well...
我拿到了 哦 好家伙
- I got 'em. - Oh, goodie.
就这里 没错 我觉得太爽了
Right here. - Yep. I feel so nasty.
Wow.
别摆那张贵格教徒进了脱衣舞俱乐部的表情
Don't give me that Quaker in a titty bar look.
我说真的 别 (严守清规的基督教派别)
Seriously, don't.
好啦...Ken给芭比套上了衬裙 (说错话) (Ken是芭比的官配男友)
Here we go... Ken's given Barbie the slip.
好吧 伙计们
Okay, guys,
向那些可能误解了那首歌的人
to those who may have misinterpreted the song,
我们向他们表示歉意
we, to them, offer apologies,
尤其是我们最亲切的东道主
especially our most gracious host
芬兰总理
the Prime Minister of Finland.
那里发生了什么?
So what's going on back there?
我只知道国防部长
All I know is the Secretary of Defense
去见了Kent
has been in to see Kent.
我得去睡了 Amy
I must go to sleep now, Amy.
我的时差和你一样...被赫尔辛基化了
I'm on your time... Helsinchronized.
哦 好吧 我觉得我同时呆在了两个时区
Yeah, well, I feel like I'm on two time zones at the same time.
我或许是第一个来平行大姨妈的女人
I might be the first woman ever to have parallel periods.
你得去欧洲时区 Amy 而我在我的卧室里
You got to go to Europe, Amy, and I'm in my bedroom.
Sean 你得上床了
Sean, you need to come to bed now.
别想太多 我们只是睡觉而已
And lower your expectations. We will just be sleeping.
这不是次危机
It's not a crisis. Despite your standard-issue
不计较你常规的歇斯底里的洗衣妇反应 这确实不是...
hysterical washerwoman reaction, it's really not.
生命正受到威胁 你知道生命对吧?
Lives were at risk. You know lives?
在你变成亡灵之王前你曾经拥有的
Like what you had before they made you king of the undead.
你对危机管理的认知就是尖叫 我们完了! 埋了我!
Your idea of crisis management is screaming, We're fucked! Bury me!
我们完了! 埋了我!
We're fucked! Bury me!
好吧 这是Hyva Suomi 就是上 芬兰 Hyva Suomi
Okay, it's Hyva Suomi. That's Go, Finland.
好吧 Hyva Suomi 那首歌的事情过去了吗?
Okay, Hyva Suomi. And is the song thing shut down?
哦 是的 头部中弹 无影无踪
Oh, yeah. Bullet in the head, unmarked grave.
副总统女士
Madam Vice President.
总理女士
Madam Prime Minister.
欢迎您来芬兰 我很高兴
I am delighted to welcome you to Finland.
谢谢 请叫我Selina
Thank you. And please call me Selina.
Selina 什么?
Selina. - Yes?
抱歉? 什么?
Excuse me? - What?
我们可以开始了吗 哦 是的 是的
- Shall we begin? - Oh, yes. Yes.
您愿意领路么 是的 是的
- Would you like to lead the way? - Yes, yes.
哦 您愿意先行吗? 哦 我们可以...
- Oh, you'd like to go first? - Oh, we can...
一起走?好吗? 一前一后
We Can go together? Yes? - in tandem.
是吗?是吗? 我们得走了
Yes? Yes? - We Shall go.
我为您准备了一份礼物
I have a gift for you.
我们希望当您来我们国家的时候 您会去钓鱼
We hope that when you come to our country, you will go fishing.
因为没人会招待我?
Because no one will feed me?
因为您喜爱钓鱼
Because you love fishing.
实际上 并不 真令人困惑
I don't, actually. How baffling.
不 但这仍是份漂亮的礼物
No, but it is still a beautiful gift.
我同样有份
I also have a gift for you
著名芬兰鸟的礼物给您
of famous Finnish birds.
哦 哦 天哪
Oh. Oh, my goodness.
哦 天哪
Oh, my.
哦 我可以 我可以 谢谢
Oh, I have it. I have it.
真是一只漂亮的钟
Thank you. What a lovely clock
上面还有只...特殊的鸟儿
with an unusual bird.
这是愤怒的小鸟
It's an Angry Bird.
它为什么那么愤怒?
And why is it so angry?
因为它要摧毁所有的猪
Because it wants to destroy all of the pigs.
哦 当然 它是只愤怒的小鸟
Oh, of course. It's an Angry Bird.
那是个应用 电脑游戏
It is an app. It is a computer game.
这是我们送给您的一个成功的芬兰输出产品
It is a successful Finnish export
它反映了芬兰
that we give to you to reflect Finland's place
作为软件创新先锋的地位
as a pioneer of software innovation.
确实 我很迷它
Indeed. I'm a huge fan.
您玩过? 当然 当然
You have played it? - Yes. Yes.
尽管游戏中的暴力是个问题
Although violence in games is a concern.
但在这里
But in this case, it's great fun
在游戏里干掉所有的猪实在是很有意思
to kill the pigs
(大段芬兰语...)
in a game, of course.
题记... 嗯?
the inscription... - Yes?
是的 它说
Yes, it reads, Finland,
芬兰 你笨重而庞大
you are hefty.
唔嗯 这个词有误
Uh-uh. That is the wrong word.
哦 当然 很讽刺 不是吗?
Oh. Yes, it is ironic, no?
因为美国人的体重指数比芬兰人的高得多
Because Americans have a much greater body mass index than the Finns.
啊 那就是我最近发起
Ah, which is why I have recently launched
“动起来”运动的原因
my Get Moving campaign,
它专门针对肥胖
which is aimed specifically at the obese
以及病态肥胖
and the morbidly obese.
你为何如此厌恶数字?
Why do you hate numbers so much?
哦 上帝啊 你没被你数学老师骚扰过 对吗
Oh, God, you weren't molested by your math teacher, were you?
到这里面来 哦
Let's go in here. Oh.
嘿 Mike 呃...
- Hey, Mike. - Uh...
你好 Kent 我们有个问题 Mike
- Hi, Kent. - We have a problem, Mike.
我会尽快给你统计总结 先生
I'm gonna get you the stat summary ASAP, sir.
我是统计织梦者
I am a Metric Dreamweaver.
这和统计梦没关系
This is not a Dream Metric issue.
你知道索伦之眼吗?
Are you familiar with the Eye of Sauron?
能见一切之眼
Fire-rimmed, all-seeing eye
托尔金的《魔戒》里以火为界
from Tolkien's Lord of the Rings.
我想我某次在飞机上听过
I think I caught it on a plane once.
索伦之眼眼几乎完美地体现了当代媒体的特点
The Eye of Sauron is the near perfect analogue for the modern media.
如果我们能把那眼睛导向赫尔辛基
If we can draw the Eye to Helsinki,
那么没人会关心这儿发生了什么
then it won't be looking at what's going on here.
那么这儿到底发生了什么?
And what is exactly going on here?
我可没法告诉你 Mike
I cannot tell you that, Mike.
那Selina是咕噜姆(《魔戒》中的怪物)
Is Selina Gollum?
不 不 不 听够那些废料了
No, no, no. Enough of that ear swill.
现在发生了我认为在发生的事情吗 Kent?
Is what's going on what I think is going on, Kent?
你现在在当衣帽间服务小妹了?
Are you working as a hatcheck girl now?
哦 棒极了 你看到了吗
Oh, great. Did you see that?
那是他妈的司法部长
The Attorney fucking General.
瞧 我们都知道谎言比犯罪更糟糕
Look, we all know that the lie is worse than the crime.
瞧 你正点头
Look, you're nodding your head,
但你不知道他妈的我在说什么
but you don't know what the fuck I'm talking about.
那首歌 它 捂住耳朵 Mike
- The song, it's... - Close your ears, Mike.
乌兹别克斯坦的其中一个人质是间谍
One of the hostages in Uzbekistan was a spy.
现在 有人知情 但是完全没打算通知国会
Now, some people knew and didn't bother to inform Congress.
其他人 比如Selina 则被蒙在鼓里
Other people, like Selina, did not know.
她曾公开否认有间谍
She went on record denying that there was a spy.
那么在未来的13个月里
So for the next 13 months,
我们就会一直玩谁什么时候知道了什么事
we're gonna play who knew what when.
然后我们当中的某些人就得下岗去做巡回演说
Then some of us are gonna go off on the lecture circuit
另一些会直接进监狱
and some of us are gonna go off to prison.
现在你可以摇头了
Now you can shake your head.
苍天啊 我讨厌了解内幕
Christ, I hate knowledge.
请允许我介绍我的丈夫
May I introduce, please, my husband?
Osmo Hakkinen.
你好
How do you do?
哦 真可心
Oh! How lovely.
自1835年以后华盛顿就不再这么做了
That hasn't happened in Washington since 1835.
很荣幸见到您
It is a pleasure to meet you.
尽管您没有高歌一曲让我有些失望
Although I'm a little bit disappointed you've not serenaded us.
哦 那首歌
Ah, the song.
哦 我希望您能明白那完全是开玩笑的
Well, I hope you realize that that was entirely in jest.
是的 事实上 是那个我被冒犯了的推测
Yes. In fact, it is the presumption of offense
冒犯了我
that has offended me.
哦 好吧 我们无意冒犯
Oh, well, no offense was intended.
但你的传媒主管有专门向我道歉
But your communications director apologized specifically to me.
这让人觉得我大概缺乏幽默感或者狭隘 我是个下等人 (nieder 德语)
This gives the impression that I am somehow humorless or petty. I am neider.
她是下等人 不 她是下等人
- She is neider. - No, she's neider.
能失陪一小会么?
Would you please excuse us for just one moment?
嗯? 就一会 嗯
- Yes? - For a moment, yeah.
那首歌
So that song, unlike your career
和你传媒主管的职业生涯不同 它还不会完
as communications director, will not die.
所以现在你得去为这个道歉而道歉
So now you must go and apologize for the apology.
是的 女士 那你为什么还站在这?
- Yes, ma'am. - Why are you still standing right here?
哦 他来了 维珍(处男)大西洋
Oh, here he comes. Virgin Atlantic.
好吧 伙计们
Okay, guys, I want to apologize
我想为之前暗示
for suggesting that the prime minister
总理个人可能被那首歌冒犯而道歉 成吗?
may have been somehow personally offended by the song, okay?
是我的责任 我的错
That's on me. That's my bad.
大概一小时后你会来为这个再次致歉吗
Are you gonna be apologizing for this in about an hour or so?
不好意思? 哎呀 这个歉也道得太快了吧
- Sorry? - Blimey, that was quick.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们应该将这种
We should keep this causing offense
冒犯-道歉的循环保持下去 哦
And then apology cycle going. - Oh.
您可以踩我的裙子 我可以对您的饮料打喷嚏
You could step on my dress. I could sneeze in your drink.
这真有趣 很有趣
- It's funny. - It is funny.
我可以说您有个形状奇怪的头
I could say you have a weird-shaped head.
当然您没有
Which of course you don't.
您的头形很完美 总理女士
You have an ideal head, Madam Prime Minister.
但我很轻松 因为您很有幽默感
But I'm very relieved that you have a sense of humor about it.
哦 芬兰人的幽默可是很出名的
Oh, the Finns are famous for their sense of humor.
哦 您知道Aki Kaurismak的作品吗? (芬兰大导演)
Oh. - Do You know the work of Aki Kaurismaki?
哦 那个网球运动员? 不是
- Oh, the tennis player? - No.
不 我是在开玩笑 我在开玩笑
No. I'm joking. I'm joking now.
实际上 我们美国人同样因我们的幽默感而闻名
In fact, we in America are also famous for our sense of humor.
是的
Yes.
但认真的说
But seriously, I'm so pleased about the agreement
我很高兴今天我们能签下那项协议
that we were able to sign today.
啊 Dan歉歉...
Ah, Danteeksi.
Anteeksi...芬兰语中是抱歉的意思
Anteeksi... in Finnish it means I'm sorry.
但媒体加了个Da...
But the press have added Da...
D... 哦 不
- D... - Oh, no.
弄成了Dan歉歉 你明白吗
To make Danteeksi. Do you get it?
很有趣 你知道众人皆知芬兰人的
Very amusing. - You know the Finns are known
幽默感 很明显 哦
- for their sense of humor. - Clearly, yeah.
Dan歉歉 我得提前向你道歉
Danteeksi, I need to apologize to you in advance
因为我想这会变成
because I think that this is going to be.
永不休止的抱歉
The Never Ending Sorry.
是的
Yes!
与故事相对
As opposed to story.
没错 是的
Yes. - Yes.
这是个棒极了的国家
It's a wonderful country.
晚上好
Good evening.
副总统办公室 现在是下午两点 Sue
Office of the Vice President. It's 2:00 P.M., Sue.
你是在吃抗精神病药还是在赫尔辛基?
Are you on antipsychotics or in Helsinki?
我需要你填满副总统的日程
I need you to engorge the VP's schedule.
我要她迷翻赫尔辛基民众
I want her charming the Helsinki people.
你想要我填塞她的日程表?
You want me to pad the veep's schedule?
为什么 先生?
Why, sir?
总统想和人握手以及收获老女人的笑容
POTUS wants hands shaken and old women grinned at.
请当它是无情的事实接受这个必须的任务
Please accept the necessity of this as brute fact.
从我们到这的那一刻起 我所做的就是道歉
Ever since we got here, all I've been doing is apologizing.
好吗?我为活动取消道歉
Okay? I've been apologizing for cancelling events,
然后为重新举办再次道歉
then apologizing for putting them back on.
然后为道歉而道歉
Then apologizing for apologizing.
我说 我就是个他妈的笑柄
I mean, I'm a fucking laughingstock.
如果你要哭的话 麻烦离这条裙子远点
If you burst into tears, stay away from this dress.
Mike.
Amy 记得我们是怎么说
Amy, remember how we said
没有一个学生是间谍的吗
that none of the students was a spy
因为如果其中任何一个是间谍
because if one of them was a spy, it would have endangered
就会让其他三个不是间谍的学生受到生命的威胁
the lives of the other three who were not spies?
结果其中一个就是间谍
Turns out one of them was a spy.
都还好吗 嘿 Dan歉歉
- Everything okay? - Hey, Danteeksi.
Amy?喂?
Amy? Hello?
你还在吗 去他妈的蠢货
- You still there? - Fucking prick.
唔 总统对副总统说那是扯淡
Um, the president told the veep that was bullshit
然后她公开宣称那是扯淡
and she is on record saying that's bullshit.
让她远离媒体
Just keep her away from the press.
已经把她隔离了 因为那首歌
She's already on lockdown 'cause of the song.
我该给她戴上铁面具么
Shall I put her in an iron mask?
哦 好主意
Yeah, great idea.
您会介意
Would you be offended
我和财政部长说句话吗
if I just had a quick word with the finance minister?
哦 不 一点也不
Oh, no, not at all.
Minna.
您的妻子很可爱
Your wife is so lovely.
是的 我是个非常幸运的男人
Yes, I'm quite a fortunate man.
哦 您是 多美好的事啊
Well, you are. What a lovely thing to say.
我想抽烟想疯了
I'm dying for a smoke.
哦 是的 男孩 说对人了
Oh, yeah. Boy, tell me about it.
我可以抽一根 唔 唔 唔
I could use a cigarette myself. Mm, mm, mm.
您不是说... 是的 那会很棒
- I don't suppose that you... - Yes, that would be wonderful.
这是给我拎包的 Gary Walsh
This is my bag man Gary Walsh.
这位是总理的丈夫
This is the prime minister's husband.
Osmo Hakki...enenen.
我想 在芬兰 拎包人是kassi
I believe in Finland bag man is kassi.
是的
Yes.
哦 外头见
Well, I'll see you outside.
好的 好的 十分感谢
Yes, yes. Thank you very much.
哦 那给他留下了深刻的印象 没错
- Ooh, that impressed him. - Yeah.
好吧 这是你的第六支烟了
Okay, this is cigarette number six for you.
哦 你需要他妈的镇定 Judy法官( 法律节目)
Okay, you need to calm the fuck down, Judge Judy.
一整天我都他妈的在谈判
I've been negotiating my ass off all day.
还有 这是第五支 顺便说
And it's number five, by the way.
我只是想避免事故
I just want to avoid an incident.
芬兰人很反对吸烟
The Finns are very antismoking.
冷静 kassi
Cool it, kassi.
Mm.
这真是放松 没错
- That's a relief. - Yes.
我想这实在是太棒了 您是如此地支持Minna的事业
I think it's just wonderful how supportive you are
她的工作 您明白吗
of Minna's career, her job, you know?
哦 好吧 只是芬兰的总理而已
Oh, well, it's only the Prime Minister of Finland.
权力还没有克利夫兰的市长大
Less power than the Mayor of Cleveland.
您的特勤局特工看起来和我的一样强悍
Your Secret Service look about as tough as mine.
我们该让他们打起来吗?
Shall we get them to fight?
虽然这些香烟是
Although, seeing as these cigarettes are the thing
最有可能干掉我的东西
that's most likely going to kill me,
可如果我的特勤...
I'm surprised that my Secret S...
老天啊
Jesus.
嘿 嘿 我给你拿了些可以清洁口气的东西
Hey. Hey, I got you some breath fresheners.
有Altoids(强力薄荷糖)还有一些口香糖
I got you some Altoids and I got you some gum.
Gary 我的胸部
Gary, my boob.
什么
What?
他抓了它 什么?
He grabbed it. - What?
我是美利坚合众国的副总统
I'm the Vice President of the United States of America.
他刚刚像挤压气球一样揉捏了我的乳房
He just squeezed my tit like a balloon.
Mm-mmm. - Mm-hmm.
好吧 我去揍他
Okay, I'm gonna go mess him up.
告诉我 Selina
Just let me know. - Selina.
你还好吗?你很苍白
Are you quite feeling all right? You're very pale.
也许你需要去庭院里呼吸些新鲜空气
Perhaps you should go to the courtyard, get some fresh air.
不用了 谢谢 不用?
- No, thank you. - No?
不用
No.
这是Erkki
This is Erkki.
他是我们经济发展部的头
He is our head of economic development.
是的 他只有两件轶事
Yes, he has only two anecdotes.
没有一件值得听
Neither of them is worth hearing.
嘿 女士 我刚收到白宫来的短信
Hey, ma'am, I just got a text from the White House.
啊 希望一切正常
- Ah. - Nothing bad, I hope.
只是有个重大的领土侵犯
Just a major violation of a border.
你从短信知道这个?
You get this in a text?
没错 唔哼 没错
- Yeah. - Mm-hmm, yeah.
我唯一收到的短信来自我丈夫
The only text I get is from my husband
说我又要晚回家了
saying I am being late home again.
也许是想... 嗯
Might want to... - Yeah.
呼吸 呼吸
Just breathe. Just breathe.
呼吸 哦 上帝啊
- Just breathe. - Oh, my God.
你看到了吗? 哦 天哪 怎么可能不?
- Did you see? - Oh, my God. How could you not?
你看到这个了吧? 是的 是的
did You see this? - Yes. Yes.
我去给你拿些水 他看上去就像迪士尼动画里的反派
I'm gonna get you some water. He looks like a Disney villain.
耶稣啊 Gary 你看上去像得了白血病
Jesus, Gary. You look leukemic.
我一直如此 我长这样
I always do. That's my look.
是的 哦 今晚你看上去
Yeah, well, you are rocking that look
尤其严重 我的朋友
pretty hard tonight, my friend.
怎样的一晚啊
Quite a night.
哦...我会他妈的这么说
Oh... I'll fucking say.
Gary刚刚给你短信了?
Did Gary just text you?
Gary知道了? 没错
Gary knows? - Yeah.
耶稣啊 Mike正到处说
Jesus, Mike's gone viral.
Mike?
我们正在说...
We're talking about...
关于间谍总统说了谎 Osmo猥亵了我
POTUS lying about the spy. - Osmo groped me.
什么? 什么?
What? - What?
他什么? 他他妈的做了什么?
He What? - He fucking What?
你告诉她了吗 他...他...
did You tell her? - He... He...
他告诉我那些谣言不是真的
he told me those rumors weren't true.
你能相信那个怪物么
Can you believe that monster?
等等 等等 等等 发生了什么 你说了什么
- Wait, wait, wait. What happened? - What did you say?
总统 他猥亵了她
POTUS. - He groped her.
总统猥亵了你? 不是
POTUS groped you? - No.
总统没那个种来猥亵我
POTUS wouldn't have the balls to grope me.
他知道他说了谎?
He knew and he lied?
等等 等等 知道什么?对什么说谎?
Wait, wait, knew what? Lied about what?
总统知道那个学生是间谍
POTUS knew that the student was a spy
并且没有通知国会的情报委员会
and didn't inform the Congressional Intel Committee.
去他的!去他的! 你们刚才说什么?
- Shit! Shit! - What were you talking about?
Osmo猥亵了我
Osmo groped me.
去他的!
Shit!
我们要
We need to rain down the full might
把核武库的全部火力倾向芬兰
of our nuclear arsenal on Finland.
Mm-hmm.
这就是另一件我忘记告诉你的事情
That's the other thing I forgot to tell you.
我们要炸平芬兰
We're gonna blow up Finland.
我能为您做什么? 他妈的你去哪了?
Can I help you? Where the fuck you been?
别跟我说 你一直在做民调
Don't tell me. You've been polling.
我敢说你就算拉泡屎 出来形状都是数字2 (大便的俚语)
I bet when you take a crap, it actually comes out as a number two.
听着 我们得告诉总统
Listen, we've got to tell the president
他必须承认那个学生是间谍
that he has to admit that this student was a spy.
我仍在做对照 看是否承认是最好的路线
I'm still collating whether admitting is the best course.
我不敢相信你居然还在核对那他妈的风向
I can't believe you're still checking the fucking wind direction.
我需要更多的时间 在真相显现在此种...
I need more time before the truth can emerge in such a...
Furlong众议员
Congressman Furlong.
嗯 沉默看起来在这行不通
Yeah, the blank looks are not gonna play here.
你们两个被抓到和祖母口交
You two have been caught with your balls in grandma's mouth.
每个人都在高调地谈论这个
Everybody's talking about it up on the Hill.
我知道我所知道的
I know what I know.
我不知道你认为你知道的
I don't know what you think you know.
去你妈的还有你那孔子门徒狗屎 成吗
Screw you and your Confucius grasshopper bullshit, all right?
每个人都会知道 这种事情最后都会朝那个方向发展
Everybody's gonna know. That's just the way these things go.
现在人们认为总统对那个孩子是间谍的事情撒了谎
Now people think POTUS lied about that kid being a spy.
我想知道你们这两个喜欢吞精液的瘾君子 有什么可行性建议
I want to know what you two spunk junkies propose we do about it.
抱歉 Kent 我就是有个小问题 是关于...
Sorry, Kent, I just had a quick question about...
哦 他们都知道了?Laurel和二货? (出自Laurel和Hardy 滑稽片搭档)
Oh, do they know? Laurel and Retardy?
我跟你说 Mike 我要你把这些总结加到那个发布概述里
Tell you what, Mike. I need you to add these summaries
好吗?去
to the rollout overview. Okay? Go.
哦 第二轮 好吧...
- Oh, round two. - Well...
Doyle参议员 先生们 先生们
- Senator Doyle. - Gentlemen, gentlemen.
哦 我希望我能得到我的五杯免费酒
Well, I hope I get my five free punches.
我是他妈的参议院情报委员会的主席
I'm the fucking chair of Senate Intel,
也就是说我本该被告知一切秘密行动
which means that I'm supposed to be informed of any covert action.
我们在同一条船上 好吗?
We're all on the same team here, right?
没错 一团糟号 哦 我的会员卡就在这的某个地方
Right, Team Fuckup. Yeah, I got my membership card here somewhere.
我找不到它 你得有大局观
- I can't find it. - You need to look at the bigger picture.
哦 我看到了大局
Oh, I've seen the bigger picture.
显示总统对美国人民说谎
Shows POTUS lying to the American people.
我告诉你 这不只是个危机
I'm telling you, this is not just a crisis.
这至少能让Oliver Stone拍十年电影 (导演 热爱政治题材)
This is at least 10 years of Oliver Stone movies.
没错 不是那些好的 不是《野战排》那种
Yeah, not the good ones. Not Platoon.
我说 你他妈的到底哪儿不对劲 Kent?
What the fuck is wrong with you, Kent?
说真的 当你拔出引线 你就该扔出手榴弹了
Seriously, when you pulled the pin out, you're supposed to throw the grenade away.
你不会把它黏在你那该死的屁股上
You don't stick it up your own freakin' ass.
那是我喜闻乐见的
That I'd like to see.
我需要根香烟 哦 上帝啊
- I need a cigarette. - Oh, God.
不 不是哦 上帝啊  给我该死的香烟
No, not Oh, God. Just get me the goddamn cigarette.
总统 我所支持的
The president, the one I support,
那个因工作我为之效忠的总统
the one that I am loyal to
对我说了谎
as my job, lies to me.
对吗? 唔嗯
- Right? - Mm-hmm.
好吧 在我为道歉而道歉后
Okay, after I apologized for apologizing,
我之前已经开始把那些活动重新塞回你的日程表
I started to put meet-the-people events back in your schedule.
全部取消并为此道歉
Cancel them all and apologize for cancelling.
哦 上帝啊 还要道歉?真的?
Oh, Jesus, more apologizing? Really?
I apologized less after I banged my brother's fianc閑.
我搞上我兄弟的未婚妻我都没这么道歉过
你在埋怨什么?你在开玩笑呢?
What are you bitching about? Are you kidding?
我才是那个压力重重的人 振作起来 女士
I'm the one who's under pressure. Get it together, lady.
那猥亵呢? 我说 来吧
What about the grope? I mean, come on.
谢谢 那是对美国的袭击
Thank you. - that is an attack on America.
好吗?在我看来那可以算是一次性骚扰中的911
All right? That's like a sexual 9/11 in my opinion.
或者至少是个古巴导弹危机级别的性骚扰
Or a sexual Cuban Missile Crisis at the least.
我们不可能对众公开这次猥亵
It's not like we can go public about the grope.
那会给你定性 没错
it Would define you. - Right.
你的乳房被个芬兰人
Your tit being fondled by a Finn
揉捏了会是唯一被记住的
would be all you're remembered for.
没错 你不能为此树立个雕像
- Yeah. - You can't build a statue on that.
没错 没人可以知道这个
That's right. Nobody can know about this.
好吗?尤其是Kent 哦 没错
- All right? Especially Kent. - Oh, yeah.
为什么要那么做?因为他会用此来针对我
And why is that? Because he's gonna use it against me.
猥亵局势图 没错
a grope matrix. - Right.
因为他是个男人
Because he's a man.
因为我们生活在一个男人主宰的世界
Because this is a man's world that we live in.
因为阴茎轴心
Because of the axis of dick.
这鱼很美味
This fish is delicious.
这是什么鱼? 这是鸡肉
What is this fish? - it is chicken.
鸡胸肉? 是的
the breast? - Yes.
在美国 实际上 我们称鱼肉是海洋里的鸡肉
In America we actually call fish chicken of the sea.
我喜欢鱼肉
I love fish.
有些人不喜欢它的味道
Some men do not like the taste.
我喜欢
I do.
谢谢 哦 总理女士
Thank you. Oh, Madam Prime Minister,
我还没向您介绍Gary Walsh
I don't believe I've had a chance to introduce you to Gary Walsh.
不 不 你还没有
No. No, you have not.
我是副总统的拎包人
I'm the VP's bag man,
那个我想在芬兰你们叫kassi
which I believe in Finland you say kassi.
抱歉? 我是个kassi
- Excuse me? - I'm a kassi.
你从哪知道的那个翻译?
Where did you get this translation from?
我在特区有个在使馆工作的芬兰朋友
I have a Finnish friend in DC who works at the embassy
在我来之前她教了我一些
and she gave me lessons before I came.
如你所知 kassi是包的意思
You see, kassi is bag,
但不是拎包人
but it's not bag man.
那是男人的袋子 你知道的 那个
It is a man bag. You know, rrr.
那是个容器
It is a container.
装睾丸的容器
It is a testicle container.
哦 不 别觉得羞耻 Gary
Oh, no. Don't feel ashamed, Gary.
因为 当然 你不是阴囊什么的
Because, of course, you're not a ball sack.
而且不是每个人能说自己不是...
And not everyone can say that they're not...
我很抱歉这么说…
excuse me, I'm so sorry...
阴囊
a ball sack.
甚至这张桌子上的每个人也不是都能说
Not even everyone at this very table.
Kent希望我把U盘里的地区总结加进去
Kent wants me to add these regional summaries
好了 你怎么加的?
from the thumb drive. All right, how do you add?
command键加A  Alt加Break (苹果键盘)
Command A, hombre.
我还以为是ctrl a
I always thought it was control A.
好吧 成了 发送
Okay, here we go. Send.
我去 或许就是Ctrl A
Shit, maybe it was control A.
我想你大概选择了全部
I think you might have selected all
把那个U盘里的所有资料全发出去了
and sent everything that was on that thumb drive.
那是你告诉我的 不 我没有
- That's what you told me to do. - No, I didn't.
你说了command a 不 我说的是Ctrl a
- You said command A. - No, I said control A.
你只是没有听清楚 因为你没戴上助听器
You just couldn't hear me because you didn't have your ear trumpet.
我觉得我要把这个毁尸灭迹 我能烧掉这台电脑吗?
I feel like I want to burn this thing. Can I burn this computer?
你为什么要烧那个 Mike?
Why would you burn that, Mike?
Mike?抱歉
Mike? Excuse me.
怎么了?
What's up?
我们刚把Kent关于那个间谍的民调分析发了出去
We just sent out Kent's polling consultation on the spy.
什么间谍?
What spy?
人质中有一个是间谍
One of the hostages was a spy.
哦 去你妈的 Mike
Oh, fuck you, Mike.
你就是事业毒药 你知道吗?
You're career poison. Do you know that?
上帝啊 那就是你为什么喜欢玩帆船的原因 因为你他妈的就是个锚
Jesus, that's why you like sailing, because you're a fucking anchor
把有着光明前途的事业拖到他妈的海底
dragging promising careers down to the bottom of the fucking ocean.
停 这只是阶段一的东西
Stop it. This was just phase one stuff.
范例问题大概像是如果总统说了谎怎么办?这种
Sample questions like, What if the president lied?
但还不是那个 那个听起来很糟
But not that. That sounds bad.
更间接 但还是很糟
It was more coded, which still is bad.
没错
Yeah.
我是说 不管怎么样都已经出去了 对吧?
I mean, it would have gotten out anyway, right?
呃... 这是互联网时代
Um... - this is the Internet age.
没有秘密能够守住 是的 没错 而且这里是特区
- Nothing stays a secret. - Yeah, yeah, and it's DC.
这是特区 这儿的每个人都在谈论
It's DC. Everybody here talks.
是的 瞧 我们需要做的就是保持冷静
Yeah, look, all we got to do is stay calm.
我们只需要保持冷静 继续走 避开任何...
- We just got to stay calm. - Keep walking, avoid any...
这行不通 Mike 站住
It doesn't work like that. Mike, hold up.
如果你能明白我出问题的方式 你会懂的
If you'd see the way I framed the question, you'd understand that.
好吧 等你东山再起的时候把那个告诉Oprah (著名脱口秀主持人)
Well, tell that to Oprah when you mount your comeback.
我是说 你把它发给了我以及这楼里的所有人
I mean, you sent it to me and every second bozo in the building.
不 我没有 他妈的你当时在想什么?
- No, I didn't. - What the fuck were you thinking?
瞧 你还给它标上高度机密
Look, you marked it highly confidential,
所以确保了这东西会像病毒一样快速传播
thereby guaranteeing that this thing is gonna go viral.
啊 副总统被芬兰总理的丈夫猥亵了
Uh, the vice president was groped by the Finnish prime minister's husband.
什么?你为什么要告诉我那个?
What? Why are you telling me that?
那很奇怪 是的 那非常不幸
- That's just weird. - Yeah, that's really unfortunate.
是上面的双峰还是下面的山谷区?
Was that up in the hills or down in the valley?
先生 我刚才在想索伦之眼 您知道吧?
Sir, I was thinking the Eye of Sauron, you know?
让所有注意力集中到赫尔辛基…
Keep the focus on Helsinki.
帆船
Sailing.
哦 恭喜 Kent
Well, congratulations, Kent.
你刚刚把这任总统拖倒了
You just brought down this presidency.
好吧 赫尔辛基的天气...
Well, the weather here in Helsinki has been...
冷得可怕 但是...
hellishly cold.
Kent的民调数据被发送了出去
Kent's polling data got e-mailed.
总统的间谍谎言刚刚公开了
POTUS's spy lie just went public.
好吧 我们得起程了 走吧 史上最短的问答环节
Okay, we're pulling out. Let's go, shortest Q&A ever.
Dan歉歉 Dan歉歉
Danteeksi! Danteeksi!
伙计们 好吧 我们得跟天气作斗争
Guys, okay, we've got some weather to contend with,
所以我们只能回答三个问题
so we only have time for three questions.
您会收到我的问候的
You will be hearing from me.
是吗?是吗? 没错 没错
Yes? Yes? - Yes. Yes.
再见 再见 哦
- Good-bye. - Good-bye. Oh!
还有两个问题
Two more questions.
这次访问是为了签订协议还是那首歌?
Was the visit about the agreement or the song?
我们非常满意那份协议
We are very pleased about the agreement
而且我们也达成了一致
and we are agreed on that.
而且那实际上是两个问题 所以很抱歉我们得走了
And that was actually two questions, so I'm afraid we've got to go.
在我的国家 我们会杀了
Where I come from, we kill people
那些嘲笑我们的人
for looking at us funny.
我们会溺死那些没有干任何事的人
We waterboard folks who haven't even done anything.
你强暴了我的胸
And you raped my tit.
哦... 哦 是的 你那么干了
- Oh... - Oh, yeah, you did.
所以我不会放过你的
So I'm coming for you
因为我现在就是只愤怒的小鸟...
'cause I'm an Angry Bird right now...
而你是只猪
and you're a pig.
Selina! Selina! 谢谢
- Selina! Selina! - Thank you.
你打算为间谍的事情道歉吗?
Are you going to apologize for the spy?
总统知道其中一个人质是中情局的人吗?
Did the president know that one of the hostages was CIA?
你知道吗? 我和总统同一战线
did You know? - I stand with the President.
我和总统同一战线?
I stand with the president?
我为什么那么说?
Why did I say that?
我们可以假装你没说过吗?
Can we pretend you didn't say it?
人们会怎么想我?
What will people think I mean?
就是你和总统同一战线
That you stand with the president.
我是说 那句话没有什么含糊的意思
I mean, there's not a ton of ambiguity with that one.
好吧 谁会知道被性骚扰了
Well, who knew that being sexually assaulted
还不是我这一天最糟糕的经历 嗯?
wouldn't be the worst thing to happen in my day, huh?
这可以写到回忆录里
That's something for the memoirs.
我永远不会再回来这里
I am never going back there.
没错 Dan歉歉?
- Yeah. - Danteeksi?
对不起 我很抱歉我踏上了
I'm sorry. Sorry I ever set foot
那片他妈的吃鱼 拍独立片的地狱
in that fucking fish-eating, indie film fucking hellhole.
噢 算了吧 别叨叨了
Oh, come on. Get over it.
我告诉每个人我是阴囊
I told everybody I was a scrotum.
是的 你说了 是吧?
Yeah, you did, didn't you?
那还好 您听到了吗
- It's okay. - Did you hear that?
他不是 女士 你还好吗?
- He's not. - Ma'am, are you okay?
我不知道 我猜还好 当然
I don't know. I guess so. Sure.
不
No.
我是说
I mean, would it be so hard
难道让人们别当贱人就那么难?
for people not to be assholes?
我不会知道
I wouldn't know.
您为什么在咳嗽 女士?
Why are you coughing, ma'am?
因为我感冒了
Because I caught a cold.
哦 瞧 我刚知道那个英国记者是谁
Oh, look, I just found out who that British reporter is.
怪异的男人 他就像个他妈的吵闹的幽灵 真的
The creepy guy. He was like a noisy fucking ghost, really.
他叫什么?让我用谷歌搜索下
What's his name? I'll Google him.
Dave Wickford. - Dave Wickford.
哦 这里说他离了两次婚 没有孩子
Yeah, it says divorced twice, no kids.
57个推特追随者
57 Twitter followers.
对一个记者来说那点数量是个屁 没错
That's shit for a journalist. Yeah.
欧洲曾经是我最爱的大陆
Europe used to be my favorite continent.
现在它连前五都排不上
Now it's not even in my top five.